为什么有些司机对切萨皮克湾大桥感到恐惧？
Why do some drivers dread the Chesapeake Bay Bridge?
嗯，对一些人来说，这种恐惧在上桥之前就开始了。
Well, for some, it starts before they ever are on it.
道路开始爬升，水面在两侧展开。
The road begins to climb and the water opens up on both sides.
从岸边看起来可控的景象，突然间感觉完全不同了。
And what looked manageable from the shore suddenly feels very different.
按现代标准来看，这座桥很高、暴露且狭窄。
This bridge is high, exposed, and narrow by modern standards.
一旦你上了桥，
And once you commit to it,
接下来的4.3英里就没有路肩，
there's no shoulder
也没有方便的地方可以停下来。
and no easy place to stop for the next 4.3 miles.
在航运通道处，桥面高出水面186英尺，
At the shipping channel, the deck rises 186 feet above the water,
大约相当于18层公寓楼的高度，
about the same height as an 18story apartment building
而桥塔比自由女神像还要高得多。
with bridge towers much higher than the Statue of Liberty.
更不用说，这座桥还声名在外，
Add to that that this crossing has a reputation.
很少有其他桥梁能与之相比。
Few others do.
事实上，有些司机不只是不喜欢它，
In fact, some drivers don't just dislike it,
他们甚至会雇人来
they'll actually hire someone else
替他们开车过桥。
to take the wheel and drive them across it.
但这种不安的感觉并非与这座桥的故事无关。
But that uneasy feeling is not separate from the story.
切萨皮克湾大桥之所以是现在这个样子、给人这样的感觉，
The Chesapeake Bay Bridge looks and feel the way it is
是因为它是为了解决一个非常具体的问题而建造的。
because it was built to solve a very specific problem.
马里兰州需要一座足够高的通道来跨越主要航运通道，
Maryland needed a crossing high enough to clear a major shipping channel,
足够坚固以抵御恶劣天气，
strong enough to withstand violent weather,
并且足够高效，能够以渡轮永远无法做到的方式
and efficient enough to connect the Eastern Shore to the rest of the state
将东岸与本州其他地区连接起来。
in a way fairies never could.
恰恰是那些让这座桥令人望而生畏的因素，
The very things that make this bridge intimidating
与使之成为可能的工程技术直接相关。
are directly tied to the engineering that made it possible.
在其74年的服役生涯中，这是一个随着每一代人而改变的故事。
Over its 74 years service, it's a story that has changed with every generation.
而现在，在2026年，这个故事再次发生了变化。
And now in 2026, that story has changed again.
因为这不再仅仅是一个著名的地标或世纪中期的胜利。
Because this is no longer just a famous landmark or a mid-century triumph.
这是一座承载着现代交通流量的老化通道，
It's an aging crossing carrying modern traffic,
面临着现代海上风险，
facing modern maritime risk
迫使马里兰州做出决定：
and forcing Maryland to decide
当一个旧时代的方案在截然不同的时代仍在承担着关键使命时，
what happens when an old answer is still doing an essential job
该怎么办。
in a very different era.
我叫斯科特，
My name is Scott
今天我们将以"不可能的工程"的视角，
and today we're taking an Engineering the Impossible look
来看一座过桥令人生畏、
at a bridge that is intimidating to cross,
运营复杂
complicated to operate,
且有着迷人历史的大桥。
and shaped by a fascinating history.
这就是切萨皮克湾大桥。
This is the Chesapeake Bay Bridge.
让我们《越过出口》。
Let's go beyond the exit.
切萨皮克湾大桥之所以如此让人紧张，
What makes the Chesapeake Bay Bridge so stressful
是因为它不再像是通向它的那条高速公路。
is that it stops behaving like the highway that led to it.
US50和US301在接近大桥时是六车道，每个方向三条。
US50 and US301 approach the crossing as six lanes, three in each direction.
然后大桥将其压缩为横跨海湾总共五车道，
Then the bridge compresses that down to five lanes total across the bay,
东向桥跨两条，西向桥跨三条。
two on the eastbound span and three on the westbound.
要知道，这可不是一座车流量小的超大型桥梁。
Now, this is not some oversized bridge carrying light traffic.
1952年通车时，它的年通行量仅略超过一百万辆。
When it opened in 1952, it carried just over a million vehicles.
如今，它成了这条走廊的瓶颈，
Today, it's a choke point in the corridor,
承载着现代交通需求，却用的是另一个时代的几何结构。
carrying the modern demand on geometry that was from another era.
近期每年有超过2700万辆车次从这里通过。
More than 27 million crossings a year have been pushed through here lately.
一旦你驶到水面上，
And once you're out over the water,
大桥几乎没有给你留下多少额外的操作空间。
the bridge gives you very little extra room to work with.
这也是为什么过桥的感觉与身后道路如此不同的部分原因。
Part of why the crossing feels so different from the road behind it.
它不仅又长又高，而且在风险升高的同时，空间却在收紧。
It's not just long and tall, it tightens down while the stakes go up.
马里兰州多年来一直在努力从这种几何结构中挤出更多通行能力。
Maryland has spent years trying to ring more capacity out of that geometry.
在东向交通繁忙时，
Under heavy eastbound traffic,
西向桥跨的一条车道可以反向，
one lane of the westbound span can be reversed
形成通往东岸的第三条车道。
to create a third lane heading toward the eastern shore.
在条件允许的情况下，这种设置每年使用超过200天，
Whether permitting, that setup is used more than 200 days a year,
而且这肯定是有代价的。
and it definitely comes with trade-offs.
当这种情况发生时，该桥跨上对向行驶的车辆之间没有分隔带。
There is no divider between the opposing traffic on that span when it happens.
所以，车速通常会降低，重型车辆还会面临车道限制。
So, speeds generally drop and heavier vehicles face lane restrictions.
马里兰州如今依靠架空车道控制信号、自动摆动闸门和双向通行设置，
Maryland now relies on overhead lane controls, automated swing gates, and two-way traffic setups
来让这座已无法匹配其接入道路的通道发挥更多余力。
to squeeze more life out of this crossing
that no longer matches the road feeding into it.
所以，这座桥现在不仅仅是在承载交通。
So, the bridge now is not just carrying traffic.
它几乎得像一台机器一样被管理。
It has to be managed almost like it's a machine.
而且即使这种灵活性也有其极限。
And even that flexibility has limits.
在发布大风警报期间，双向通行是被禁止的。
Two-way traffic is prohibited during wind warnings.
风速从30英里/小时到55英里/小时不等，
Anywhere from 30 mph up to 55,
达到55英里/小时时，大桥将完全关闭。
which is where they'll completely shut the bridge down.
这就是为什么司机们常说这座桥会让他们心神不宁。
And that's why drivers often say that this bridge gets in their heads.
你永远不知道驶上桥时会面对什么情况。
You never know exactly what you're going to face when you drive onto it.
好，这部分故事告诉我们目前的处境。
Now, this part of the story tells us where we are right now.
下一个问题是，马里兰州一开始是如何走到这一步的？
The next question is, how did Maryland get here in the first place?
在湾桥建成之前，切萨皮克湾不仅仅是地图上的一片水域。
Before the Bay Bridge existed, the Chesapeake was not just water on a map.
它是一道真正的交通障碍。
It was a real transportation barrier.
汽车和卡车必须依靠渡轮，
Cars and trucks had to use fairies,
而绕行海湾北端
and going around the northern end of the bay
可能意味着大约200英里的旅程，
could mean a trip of roughly 200 miles on older roads
走的是狭窄、别扭且缓慢的旧公路。
that were often narrow, awkward, and slow.
到了20世纪中叶，
By the middle of the 20th century,
整个系统已经难以为继。
that whole system was no longer keeping up.
对于东岸的居民来说，
For people on the Eastern Shore,
这道障碍以如今听起来很奇怪的方式
that barrier shaped everyday life
塑造着日常生活。
in ways that sound strange now.
正如东岸的一则记载所言，
As one Eastern Shore account put it,
对一些农民和海产品商贩来说，
for some farmers and seafood sellers,
去费城的市场往往
it could often be easier to reach the markets in Philadelphia
比费力地走漫长的公路去巴尔的摩更容易，
than to fight the long road to Baltimore,
这正说明了在建桥之前，
which just shows how before the bridge,
海湾不仅仅分隔了两条海岸线。
the bay did not just separate two shorelines.
它扭曲了整个州的地理版图。
It warped the whole map of the state.
建桥的压力已酝酿多年。
Pressure for a bridge had been building for years.
立法最终于1938年推动。
Legislation finally moved in 1938.
随后第二次世界大战将项目推迟。
Then World War II pushed the project back.
直到1947年，
It wasn't until 1947,
特别是在州长小威廉·普雷斯顿·莱恩的领导下，
specifically under Governor William Preston Lane Jr.,
州政府才终于承诺
that the state finally committed to building a fixed crossing
在桑迪角和肯特岛之间修建一座固定通道。
between Sandy Point and Kent Island.
然而，即便如此，许多人仍然认为这整个想法是鲁莽的。
Even then, though, many people thought that the whole idea was reckless.
在成为地标之前，湾桥是一场巨大的赌博，
Before it became a landmark, the Bay Bridge was a big gamble,
一次雄心勃勃的尝试，试图在马里兰州最大的障碍之一上强修一条永久性道路。
a hugely ambitious attempt to force a permanent road across one of Maryland's biggest obstacles.
渡轮不可能永远维持下去。
Fairies could not keep pace forever.
虽然它们的运输数量听起来惊人，
And while their numbers sound staggering,
但每年仅能运送约10万辆车次穿越海湾。
they were only able to move about 100,000 vehicles annually across the bay.
作为对比，大桥通车的1952年，
For a backdrop to that number, the first year the bridge was opened in 1952,
第一年就承载了近110万辆车次。
it hosted nearly 1.1 million vehicles.
所以，决定建桥是一回事，
So deciding to build a bridge was one thing.
弄清楚哪种桥梁能真正在这里行得通则是另一回事。
Figuring out what kind of bridge could actually work here quite another.
人们对湾桥——至少是1952年建成的原始桥跨——最先注意到的特征之一，是它几乎看起来像有人试图建造一个美国所有桥梁类型的样品套装。
One of the first things people notice about the Bay Bridge, at least the original span that was built in 52, is that it almost looks like somebody tried to build a sample kit of every bridge type in America.
但这种混合外观是有其用途的。
But that mixed look has a purpose.
没有任何一种单一设计能完成全部任务。
No single design could do the whole job.
在西岸附近，
Near the Western Shore,
桥梁必须升得足够高以跨越主航运通道。
the bridge had to rise enough to clear the main shipping channel.
湾桥的其他部分不需要这种结构，
Other parts of the Bay Bridge didn't need that kind of structure,
所以通道随着海湾本身而变化。
so the crossing changed with the bay itself.
悬索桥承载着主通道上方的道路。
Suspension spans carried the road over the main channel.
悬臂和桁架部分处理其他通航开口。
Canol lever and truss sections handled the other navigational openings.
在较浅水域和航运需求不同的地方，
Lower beam and girder approaches took over
较低的梁桥和连续梁引桥接替了任务。
where the water was shallower and the demands of shipping traffic were different.
这种混合设计值得注意，
That mixed design is worth noticing
因为它有助于解释
because it helps explain why the bridge
为什么这座桥即便到现在开起来仍然感觉如此不同寻常。
still feels so unusual to drive even now.
连大桥的那个大弯道也源自功能，而非美学。
Even the bridge's big curve comes from function, not aesthetics.
主跨必须以直角跨越航运通道，
The main span had to cross the shipping channel at a right angle
而这个要求塑造了驾驶体验本身。
and that requirement shaped the drive itself.
但在图纸上解决通道问题只是挑战的一部分。
But solving the crossing on paper was only part of the challenge.
在实地建造它则是完全另一个问题。
Building it out there was another problem entirely.
原始通道由巴尔的摩的J. Grinder公司设计，
The original crossing was designed by Baltimore's J Grinder Company
主要钢构件由Bethlehem Steel制造。
with major steel components fabricated by Bethlehem Steel.
超过2000名工人投入了超过600万工时，
More than 2,000 workers spent over six million man-hour on the project
钢构件通过驳船运来，
with steel sections carried out by barge
由浮式起重机和固定式起重机吊装到位。
and lifted into place by floating and fixed cranes.
施工期间，一些工人甚至住在浮动旅馆里。
Some workers were even housed in a floating hotel during construction.
它必须逐步向开阔水域推进建造。
It had to be built progressively farther out over open water.
这是一项大型且艰巨的海上工程，
Under the conditions of a large and demanding marine job,
在上部结构安装是一项重大任务的同时，
while fitting the superructure was a major task,
更艰难的战斗发生在水线以下。
the harder fight was found below the water line.
施工人员面对的不是方便的浅层基岩。
Crews were not working with convenient shallow bedrock.
切萨皮克湾只有深厚的沉积物、淤泥和埋藏的地层，
The Chesapeake only offered deep sediments, mud, and buried layers
这使得湾底远不如
that made the bay floor far less cooperative
建成后的大桥所显示的那么合作。
than the finished bridge actually makes it look.
第一项工作是创建稳定的桥墩基础。
The first job was to create a stable pier foundation.
首先建造巨大的钢制模板——称为沉箱，
Enormous steel forums called quesons were built first,
然后将其沉入湾底。
then sunk to the bottom of the bay.
为了将它们固定到位，以不同角度穿过沉箱打入桩柱，
To hold them in place, piles were driven down through them at different angles,
希望能通过摩擦力在底部获得抓力。
hoping to gain a purchase through friction at the bottom.
之后，将一种特殊的水下固化混凝土注入每个沉箱，
After that, a special mix of underwater curing concrete was injected into each one
以置换内部的水。
to displace the water inside.
这些基础被允许固化，然后封顶，
These foundations were allowed to cure and then capped
桥墩就建在它们上面，以承载上部结构。
and the peers were built on top of those to carry the superructure.
工人们在这里需要达到的精度
The precision that workers had to achieve here
通常在大多数情况下在半英寸以内，
was usually within a half an inch in most situations,
考虑到那是在20世纪50年代初，这似乎几乎荒谬。
which seems almost absurd considering it was the early 1950s.
他们没有GPS，没有计算机模型。
They had no GPS, no computer models.
然而，从大桥今天的地位来看，
And yet, it's obvious with the bridgeg's status today,
显然建造它的人并不缺乏技术。
there was no lack of skill in building it.
那座1952年的原始桥跨确实是一项了不起的成就。
That original 1952 span was quite an achievement.
它不是一座简单的桥梁重复数英里。
It wasn't one simple bridge repeated for miles.
它是一堆问题，
It was a stack of problems
以及由艰难的通道条件所迫的一堆更大的解决方案。
and an even larger stack of answers forced by a difficult crossing.
但一旦那个问题被解决，它实际上又创造了另一个问题。
But once that problem was solved, it actually created another one.
当第一座桥跨于1952年7月30日开通时，
When the first span opened on July 30th, 1952,
它并没有被当作普通的基础设施来对待。
it was not treated like ordinary infrastructure.
当时，它是世界上最长的水上钢桥。
At the time, it was the world's longest overwater steel bridge.
对马里兰州来说，这是与过去真正的决裂。
For Maryland, it was a genuine break with the past.
曾经受天气、等待和不确定性影响的渡轮通道，
What had been a ferry crossing shaped by weather, waiting, and uncertainty
现在变成了一条直接横跨海湾的公路。
was now a direct road right across the bay.
所有那些都已被绕开，这听起来像是一场巨大的胜利。
All of that had been bypassed, and that sounds like a huge triumph.
而在当时，这确实是。
And for the time, it definitely was.
但这也意味着，
But it also meant that the bridge started aging
这座桥几乎立刻就进入了下一个问题的老化期。
into its next problem almost immediately.
它不仅仅是在满足需求，它也在创造需求。
It wasn't just serving demand. It was also creating it.
而这，确实是切萨皮克湾大桥的核心矛盾。
And really, that's a contradiction at the heart of the Chesapeake Bay Bridge.
它以奇迹之姿开放，但没过多久就不再显得容量过剩了。
It opened as a marvel, but it didn't stay oversized for long.
可以说，它成了自身成功的受害者。
You could say it became a victim of its own success.
这座通道使东岸更加可达，
The crossing made the Eastern Shore more reachable
当然也减少了对渡轮的依赖，
and it cut dependence on the fairies, of course,
但同时也将旅游、通勤和商业拉入了一个新时代。
and yet it helped pull tourism, commuting, and commerce into a new era.
这种成功是有代价的。
That success came with a cost.
原始桥梁只有两条车道，每个方向一条，
The original bridge carried only two lanes, one in each direction,
而交通增长如此之快，
and traffic growth came so quickly
以至于马里兰州在一代人之内就开始规划更多容量。
that Maryland was already planning for more capacity within a generation.
1969年，在第一条桥跨以北约450英尺处，
In 1969, construction began on a second span
第二座桥跨开工建设。
about 450 ft north of the first one.
1973年6月28日，那座新的三车道桥梁通车。
And on June 28th, 1973, that new threelane bridge opened to traffic.
1973年的西向桥跨不仅仅是
Now, the 73 westbound span was not simply a copy
第一座桥的复制品。
of the first bridge.
它反映了二十年的工程变革，以及不同的施工方式，上部结构由US Steel的美国桥梁部门建造，下部结构由Raymond Dravo Langenfelter负责。
It reflected two decades of engineering change and a different construction effort with the American Bridge Division of US Steel building the superructure and Raymond Dravo Langenfelter handling the substructure.
不变的是，Grryer仍然是该项目的设计和监理工程师。
What remained the same was Grryer remained the design and supervising engineer of the project.
较新的桥跨在细节上也明显更加现代化。
The newer span was also visibly more modern in its details.
它采用了水平塔架支撑，而不是原始桥跨上使用的X形支撑。
It used horizontal tower bracing rather than X bracing that was used on the original span.
而且斜拉索不是位于水面高度，
And the cable stays rather than being at the water level
而是位于桥面高度。
were at the bridge deck level.
这不仅仅是更多的桥。
It was not just more bridge.
这是马里兰州让这座跨海通道适应交通需求的下一次尝试。
It was Maryland's next attempt to adapt the crossing to traffic demands.
第一座桥跨很快就无法满足需求了。
The first span had quickly outgrown.
所以人们今天穿越的这座桥实际上是两个不同时代的产物。
So the bridge people cross today is really the product of two different eras.
第一座桥跨是为了终结渡轮瓶颈而建造的，
A first span that was built to end the ferry bottleneck
并证明了海湾确实可以通过公路穿越。
and proved that the bay could be crossed by a road at all.
第二座桥跨则是在后来建成的，
The second span came later after traffic had grown enough
当时交通量已经增长到足以证明最初的方案本身已不够用了。
to show that the original answer was no longer big enough on its own.
而它所创造的就是
And what it created is the bridge
马里兰州自那以后一直在使用的这座桥。
that Maryland has been living with ever since.
一个已有50多年历史的解决方案，至今仍在艰难地勉力维持。
The solution that's over 50 years old, still struggling to keep up.
到了那时，困难的部分已不再是在海湾上架起一座桥。
By then, the hard part was no longer getting a bridge across the bay.
困难的部分是马里兰州已经离不开这座桥了。
The hard part was that Maryland had become dependent on one.
切萨皮克湾大桥太重要不能失去，太繁忙不能关闭，
The Bay Bridge was too important to lose, too busy to shut down,
也太难以在短时间内被替换。
and too difficult to replace on a quick timetable.
从那时起，这座桥的故事就变成了管理、维修和风险的故事。
From that point on, the story becomes one of management, repair, and risk.
也是从那时起，这座桥开始给人一种不同的感觉。
And it's also where the bridge began to feel different.
不再是一座马里兰州建成的奇迹，而是一个该州不得不不断修补、保护和谨慎运营的通道，
Not a marvel Maryland had built, but a crossing that the state had to keep patching, protecting,
因为有太多东西依赖它。
and carefully operating because too much depended on it.
桥梁安全也是其中的一个重要因素。
Bridge safety was a major factor of that as well.
2008年，一辆牵引拖车撞穿了部分护栏，
In 2008, a tractor trailer crash tore through part of the barrier
导致卡车坠入海湾。
and sent the truck into the bay.
随后的调查指向了比单一起事故更令人担忧的问题。
The investigation that followed pointed to something more troubling than a single wreck.
护栏系统本身的某些部分已被腐蚀削弱。
Parts of the barrier system itself had been weakened by corrosion.
这就是那种揭示切萨皮克湾大桥已经成为什么的时刻。
That was the kind of moment that showed what the Bay Bridge had become.
一座日渐老化的基础设施，而该州却无法承受没有它的后果。
An aging piece of infrastructure that the state couldn't afford to do without.
从那时起，这座桥的后期生涯
And from there, the bridge's later life starts to read
就像一场漫长的保护之战。
like a long preservation fight.
东行方向的桥面已经更换过一次。
The eastbound deck had already been replaced once.
西行方向的桥跨也经历了一次大规模的修复。
The westbound span went through a major rehabilitation as well.
到2010年代中期，马里兰州仍在
By the mid 2010s, Maryland was still finding
以更隐蔽的方式发现这座桥的老化迹象。
the bridg's age in more hidden ways, too.
两座桥跨的主悬索进行了重新包裹，
The main suspension cables on both spans were rewrapped and fitted with a special dehumidification system
并安装了一套特殊的除湿系统，
to seal out moisture, dry the cables from inside,
以隔绝湿气、从内部干燥缆索并减缓进一步的腐蚀。
and slow further corrosion.
该项目于2012年秋季开始，2015年完成。
The project began in the fall of 2012 and was completed by 2015.
该州还改变了桥梁本身的交通管理方式。
The state also changed how traffic was handled on the bridge itself.
不再依赖更多的人工变道和较慢的设置，
Instead of relying on more manual lane changes and slower setup,
这座跨海通道安装了自动化车道控制系统，
the crossing was fitted with an automated lane control system using overhead signals and gates
使用高架信号灯和闸门，
so crews could close lanes, reverse traffic patterns,
使工作人员能够关闭车道、逆转通行模式，并在情况变化时更快地做出响应。
and respond faster when conditions changed.
即使所有的自动化交通控制和安全意识措施都已到位，
Even with all of the automated traffic control and safety awareness in place,
日益增长的交通量加上维持桥梁运行所必需的施工作业，
the increased traffic combined with the construction necessary to keep the bridge going
几乎可以保证事故的发生，尤其是在如此狭窄的走廊中。
almost guarantees accidents will happen, especially in such a tight corridor.
根据该州在2017年至2022年间进行的一项研究，
According to a study between 2017 and 2022 performed by the state,
切萨皮克湾大桥平均每年发生近100起事故，
the Chesapeake Bay Bridge averages nearly a 100 accidents per year,
包括因大雾和天气导致的多车连环相撞，
including multi-car pileups from fog and weather
以及奇怪的是，因分心驾驶导致的事故数量也在增长。
and strangely a number that have grown from distracted drivers.
而每次事故发生，
And every time one occurs,
都会将安全问题重新推到每个人的心头。
it jolts safety back to the forefront of everyone's mind.
这种担忧即将迎来又一次重大冲击。
That concern was about to receive another major jolt.
2024年，巴尔的摩的弗朗西斯·斯科特·基大桥坍塌
In 2024, the world was shocked
震惊了世界。
by the collapse of Baltimore's Francis Scott Key Bridge.
大多数人记得在视频中看到那些画面。
Most people remember seeing the images in the video play out.
许多人不太记得清楚的是，为什么坍塌如此彻底。
What many don't remember as clearly is why the collapse was so complete.
这座桥被集装箱船"多莉"号撞上，
The bridge was struck by the container ship Dolly
当时该船在桥附近失去了电力、推进力和舵效。
after the vessel lost electrical power, propulsion, and steering near the bridge.
当它撞上一根关键的支撑桥墩时，整个结构轰然倒塌。
When it hit a critical support pier, the structure gave way.
这是一场看似不可能发生的灾难。
It was a disaster that seemed too impossible to happen.
事故之后，这迫使马里兰州提出另一个棘手的问题。
In the aftermath, it forced Maryland to ask another hard question.
切萨皮克湾大桥能经受住
Could the Bay Bridge survive being struck
那种让基大桥倒塌的现代船只的撞击吗？
by the kind of modern ship that brought the key to its knees?
答案是响亮的"不能"。
That answer was a resounding no.
事实上，调查确定
In fact, from the investigation, it was determined
切萨皮克湾大桥可能是全国最脆弱的桥梁之一。
that the Bay Bridge may be one of the most vulnerable in the entire nation.
马里兰州对切萨皮克湾大桥的应对方案是
Maryland's answer at the Bay Bridge is a protection project
一个估计耗资1.75亿美元的保护项目。
at an estimated cost of $175 million.
该系统目前正在推进中，
That system is being advanced now,
但仍处于设计、建造和采购阶段，
but it is still in the design, build, and procurement phase,
而不是已经完工矗立在水面上，
not sitting finished out on the water,
这就引出了马里兰州现在对这座桥提出的问题——
which brings Maryland to the question it is asking about this bridge right now.
它的未来是什么？
What comes after it?
马里兰州不再假装再多修补几次就能解决整个问题。
Maryland is no longer pretending a few more repairs will solve the whole problem.
一项针对该桥的多年研究刚刚在去年完成。
A multi-year study of the bridge was concluded just this last year.
而在2026年下半年，马里兰州交通管理局宣布
And in the latter part of 2026, Maryland Transit Authority announced
将采用被称为"方案C"的计划，
that it would be adopting the plan labeled option C,
即在现有跨海通道附近建造两座带有全路肩的新四车道桥跨，
two new four-lane bridge spans with full shoulders built near the existing crossing
并最终拆除和移除现有桥跨。
and the eventual demolition and removal of the current spans.
根据当前的研究时间表，最终的联邦决定预计在2026年做出。
Under the current study timeline, the final federal decision is expected in 2026.
最终设计将于2028年开始，许可将在2031年跟进，
Final design would begin in 2028, permits would follow in 2031,
施工将于2032年开始。
and construction would begin in 2032.
而那个未来实际上是对现有大桥的判决。
And that future is really a verdict on the present bridge.
马里兰州现在规划的是
What Maryland is planning now is a 21st century response
对一座已超越原始方案的跨海通道的21世纪回应，
to a crossing that outgrew its original solution
正在规划一个为当今交通和航运世界而建的桥梁系统。
and planning a bridge system built for the traffic and maritime world of now.
虽然大多数人欢呼并赞许这一变革，
And while the majority of people all cheered and applauded the change,
但也有不少人对这个决定感到不满。
several were not happy with the decision.
对一些人来说，它仍然是一个美丽的地标，
For some people, it is still a beautiful landmark
是马里兰州最引以为豪的工程成就之一。
and one of Maryland's proudest engineering achievements.
但对另一些人来说，它是一座日渐老化的跨海通道，
But for others, it's an aging crossing
承载了太多太久。
that has been carrying too much for too long.
而替换它来得再快也不为过。
And that replacement cannot come soon enough.
两种反应都可以理解，但相去甚远。
Both reactions are understandable, but worlds apart.
归根结底，这座桥承担了近74年的重负，
In the end, it's pretty amazing
这本身就相当了不起。
that this bridge has been shouldering the load for nearly 74 years.
无论人们支持还是反对这一变革，
And regardless of whether someone is for or against the change,
他们似乎都同意一件事：他们离不开它。
the one thing they seem to agree on is they can't do without it.
现在，关于切萨皮克湾大桥有很多很多的故事。
Now, there are so many stories about the Chesapeake Bay Bridge.
也许你也有一个想要分享的故事。
And maybe you've got one, too, that you'd like to share.
或者也许我们今天的故事中有什么我们不应该遗漏的内容。
Or maybe there's something in our tale today that we shouldn't have missed.
如果是这样，请在评论区给我们留言。
If so, leave us a note in the comments.
我们会尽量回复每一条留言。
Now, we try to answer each and every one of those.
这座桥影响着很多人的日常生活，
This bridge affects so many people's daily lives,
我们真的很高兴能为你讲述它的故事。
and we're really glad we could tell you its story.
希望你也很享受。
Hopefully you enjoyed it too.
如果你喜欢，如果方便的话，
If you did, if you wouldn't mind reaching over right now
现在就请伸手点一下赞，
and hitting the like button,
这会告诉YouTube我们应该继续制作这样的故事。
that helps tell YouTube we should keep making stories like this one.
如果你有朋友可能也对这个故事感兴趣，
Now, if you have a friend that might also be interested in this story,
为什么不也分享给他们呢？
why not share it with them as well?
你知道，在《越过出口》，
You know, here at Beyond the Exit,
我们相信公路是我们故事的主角。
we believe that the highway is the hero of our story.
如果你喜欢这一点，
Now, if that's something you're enjoying,
为什么不订阅频道，
why don't you subscribe to the channel
加入我们这个BTE大家庭呢？
and join us on this big BTE caravan?
我们很乐意有你与我们同行。
We'd love to have you ride along with us.
你知道，在这个叫做YouTube的广阔公路上，
You know, there are a lot of places
有很多地方你可以去看看。
we know you can go check out on this great big highway called YouTube.
所以，我们感谢你与我们一起越过出口。
So, we appreciate you going beyond the exit with us.
一如既往，感谢观看，上帝保佑。
As always, thank you for watching and God bless.